<Document>
  # Path of Hunt
  The Path of Hunt focuses on gunplay and tangible items, and comes highly recommended for first-time Heretics. It's very strong in its comfort zone - which is to say, far away from its prey - but flounders in close-combat situations.

  It offers many powerful tools which will allow you to use your guns far more effectively than heathens. Ascending will make you reflect any and all projectiles that hit you.

  ## Principle of Strife
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponRevolverSerpentine" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Opens up the Path of Hunt to you.

  Allows you to transmute a pistol and a knife into a Serpentine Revolver. Makeshift Pistols and Flare Guns will both suffice.

  ## Hunter's Grasp
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TouchSpellMansus" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Your Mansus Grasp gains the ability to refill an empty bullet casing.

  ## Watchtower Striving
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HereticWatchtower" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Grants you the Watchtower Striving spell, which places a watchtower that is invisible to non-heretics and redirects bullets towards them when hit. 

  Requires a Focus.

  ## Mark of Hunt
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="TouchSpellMansus" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Your Mansus Grasp will cause your prey to be slowed for a short time.

  ## Meteoric Pouch
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HereticAmmoPouch" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Grants a ritual that allows you to transmute a pill canister and a pipe into a Meteoric Pouch, which works as a portable ammo fabricator. 

  A Meteoric Pouch can produce Meteoric Bullets, which go through walls.

  ## Serpent's Focus
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganThavenEyes" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Grants you the Serpent's Focus ability, which allows you to see living things through walls, but blacks out your vision. 

  Requires a Focus.

  ## Lion's Bane
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponSniperLionhunter" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Grants a ritual that allows you to transmute a pistol, some meat, and some eyes into a Lionhunter's Rifle. 
  
  The Lionhunter's Rifle comes full of .60 meteoric bullets, and has long-range sniper sights. When paired with Serpent's Focus, the user can cause extreme damage from a safe, hidden position.

  ## Warden's Shroud
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HereticSkaptodonCloak" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Grants a ritual that allows you to transmute a scarf, a glass shard, and a brain into a Skaptodon Cloak, which allows the wearer to become invisible while still.
  
  The Skaptodon Cloak can be active for two minutes on a full charge, and needs to be turned off for a short time before it will begin to recharge.

  ## Manhunt's Reversal
  The ascension ritual of the path of Hunt.Bring 3 handcuffed corpses to a transmutation rune to complete the ritual.

  This ritual will complete your transformation from Prey to Hunter. You will redirect all projectiles that hit you back at your foes. However, you can still be hurt by melee weapons.
</Document>